WASEEM RAZA

+923056981642 • waseemraza7214@gmail.com • Age: 23

OBJECTIVE:

To seek excellence in profession, growth in career and be associated with an esteemed organization offering a responsible and challenging position where by my education, experience, management, analytical skills and passion can best be utilized.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE:

SHIFT ENGINEER Jan 2018 – Till now

LG-Iceberg Industries

Project: Nishat Emporium Mall & Hotel, Lahore.

- Organized & planned the work according to SOP.
- Performed PPM of Mechanical, Electrical, Plumbing and Firefighting systems.
- Operation & Maintenance of Booster Pumps, FilterNox and RO Plant.
- Operation & Maintenance of Water supply lines, Drainage water lines, Steam Lines, Water features, Fire Valves and Fire sprinklers.
- Operation & Maintenance of York Centrifugal Chillers (5×600TR) + (2×300), LG Absorption Chillers (2×750TR), Cooling Towers, Chilled and Condenser water Pumps, AHU'S, FCU'S, HRU'S and Exhaust fans.

SITE INCHARGE June 2016 – Dec 2017

M.A Engineering Services International

Site: Metro Habib Cash & Carry Stores, Lahore.

Site: Sheikh Zaid Hospital, Lahore.

- Organized and planned the work.
- Supervised the maintenance and team.
- Operate and maintain the HVAC plant room.
- Performed preventive maintenance of HVAC Equipment's.
- Operation & Maintenance of Chillers, Cooling Towers, Pumps, AHU'S and FCU'S.

AMAL CAREER-PREP FELLOWSHIP

July 2017 - Sep 2017

- Education startup funded by Stanford University that teaches professional skills to student and corporations.
- Invested 3 months in order to develop business skills (e.g., communication, Leadership, Problem solving, teamwork etc.)

EDUCATION:

B.Sc. MECHANICAL ENGINEERING TECHNOLOGY

Sep 2014 - May 2018

University of Engineering & Technology, Lahore.

CGPA: 3.39/4.00

D.A.E (MECHANICAL)

Sep 2011 - July 2014

Govt. College of Technology, Multan.

Marks: 82%

MATRICULATION

May 2009 - April 2011

Govt. Pilot secondary school, Multan.

Marks: 78%

PROJECTS:

- Reassembly and assembly of an IC Engine.
- Practically Performed Bernoulli's equation.
- Design and Fabrication of Hand Operated Juice Machine.
- Field research in efficiency variation of different Power Plants.
- Developed advance techniques for Planning and Scheduling of different types of maintenance.

COMPUTER SKILLS:

• AutoCAD, ANSYS, Solid works at initial stage & MS Office (Word, Excel, PowerPoint, Access & Outlook.)

HONOURS & AWARDS:

- Got 3rd position in whole college in DAE.
- Got Best Scout Award for the year of 2016.
- Graduated from Amal Academy with Honors.

WORKSHOPS:

- Attended two days' workshop organized by ASHRE UET Branch to develop Communication skills, Mock Interviews, Interpersonal skills, Job finding etc.
- Organized many events in University as an Organizer.
- Attended seminar on "Self Awareness" at Akhuwat-AISEM.
- Organized many Scouts workshops as an organizer/Manager.

SOCITIES:

- Member of ASME UET Branch.
- Deputy Chairman of a Scout Group all over the country.
- Finance Executive at PSWO (Pakistan Students welfare Organization).

SKILLS:

- Management skills.
- Problem solving skills.
- Time management skills.
- Good team ethic approach.
- Ability to work under pressure.